艾凡斯頓  懷俄明州
我已與你為敵
I have made you an
為敵
enemy
亦與自己為敵
I have been my own
"為敵"
enemy
我在默默請祈
I am asking
你的寬恕降臨
for you to forgive me
為不堪的過去
for everything
若你難以釋懷
if you don't
那也值得憐憫
you're worthy of compassion
若你寬宏大量
if you do
你便更勝一籌
you're a better man than I am
若你心有不知
if you don't know
你我本是一家
you're my family
我內心之敵
enemy
我充滿歉意
I'm sorry
好  我會盡力而為
Ok. I'll see what I can do.
謝謝
Thanks.
我還不能確定這個案子的性質
I'm not sure what we have here
但懷俄明州尤因塔縣的Samuel治安官
but I just got a call and some case files
給我發來了一些案件卷宗
from a Sheriff Samuel in uinta county   wyoming.
6天前夜  分別發現有兩名青少年
6 nights ago   two different teens were found hanging
在自己的臥室中自盡而死
in their bedrooms.
自盡
Hanging?
發現Trish Leake時  她已窒息而死
Trish Leake was dead when she was found.
Ryan Krouse在現場被救了回來
Ryan Krouse was revived on scene
但幾天後也在醫院堨h世
but then died a few days later in the hospital.
我知道我們不處理自殺案件
I know we don't handle suicides.
但在上週五  就在附近的幾個鎮上
But the previous Friday   two more boys
發現有兩名男孩在門背後
a few towns over were found hanging
自盡而亡
on the backs of their doors.
一周內在一個鄉縣上同時發生四起自殺案
4 successful suicides in the same rural county in a week?
這高於全國平均水平
That's   uh   way above the national average.
我知道
I know.
那些孩子並不是典型的自殺群體
These kids don't fit the pattern.
不濫用毒品  酒精和抗抑鬱藥物
No drug or alcohol abuse   no antidepressants
也沒有被拘捕紀錄
No prior arrests.
他們只是平凡的好孩子
These are just plain good kids
而他們在一個週五的晚上
who decided to hang themselves
幾乎同一時刻  決定自盡了斷
at approximately the same time on a Friday night.
只有當人感到束手無措
When someone feels trapped
身陷困境  深感絕望時
in what feels like a hopeless situation
才會扣動扳機  服藥自殺或自盡而亡
pulling the trigger or swallowing pills or hanging yourself
因為在他們看來  只有這樣才能解脫
Seems like the only way out.
但對那些孩子來說  根本沒有這些跡象
None of that seems to exist here.
這其中一定有問題
Something's really wrong.
Hotch  我能感覺到
Hotch   I can feel it.
聽著  所有的自殺事件都發生在週五
Look   all these events happened on a Friday.
今天是週三
It's Wednesday.
而我們現在手頭沒有其他案件
We're not on another case right now.
好吧  將其定性為可疑死亡案件調查
All right. Generate an equivocal death investigation
大夥兒上飛機再說
and get everybody on the jet.
到時再決定這起案子是自殺還是兇殺
We will determine whether these are homicides or suicides.
即使是自殺案件
And even if they are suicides...
這其中也定有問題
There's definitely something wrong here.
正在刻盤  刻盤完成
Burn in Progress. Disk Burn Complete.
Trish Leake  Ryan Krouse
犯罪心理 第五季 第13集
Criminal Minds S05E13
生活如戲  樂在其中
"Life is a game. Play it.
生命似金  敬請珍重
Life is too precious. Do not destroy it."
特蕾莎修女[著名諾貝爾和平獎獲得者]
Mother Teresa.
長官  我不是說我不想來
Sir   it's not that I'm not glad to be coming with you
相反我很想來  只是不知道為什麼要我來
Because I am. I just don't understand the why.
進行可疑死亡案件調查
One of the aspects
會涉及到
Of an equivocal death investigation
自殺的可能性
when suicide is a probability
如此一來需要進行間接人格評估
is an indirect personality assessment.
受害人都是網絡一代的孩子
Our victims are all internet generation kids.
在評估時  應該可以利用他們的電腦上
There should be invaluable personal data
寶貴的個人資料
on their computers to mine for the evaluation.
如果他們的確是自殺
If they committed suicide
那麼證據很可能就在他們的電腦
evidence of it will probably in their cyber world.
所以要我偷窺他們的電腦嗎
So I'm gonna snoop through dead kids' computers?
坐上這架飛機通常都沒什麼好事
This plane seldom makes pleasure trips.
我們瀏覽過卷宗了
We've all been over the files.
現在來分析一下受害人特徵吧
Let's talk about victimology.
四個孩子都是正派的學生
Ok. All 4 kids were decent students
住在不同的鎮上
from different neighboring towns
但在同一個縣學校唸書
but the same school and the same county.
活躍於社區和體育活動
Active in sports and community.
家庭完整  沒有精神疾病
Intact families   no mental disorders
最近沒有發生突發事件
No precipitating events.
他們不過是普通的乖孩子
These are just average good kids.
肯定有什麼潛在問題
There has to be some underlying issue.
除了時間上的相對接近
Besides relative proximity
幾名受害人之間並無顯著關聯
there's no obvious connection between any of them.
似乎可以排除公開自殺約定這一點
It seems to rule out an overt suicide pact.
青少年自殺前的一些徵兆
The first few days leading up to a teenager's suicide
應該非常顯而易見
are usually very telling.
他們的行為極易被察覺
Their behavior is transparent.
有多種不同的指標在內
There's a multitude of indicators.
沒錯  但是這堥S有最普通的徵兆
Yeah   but the most common don't exist here.
沒有自殺的意圖
There's no prior attempts
沒有持續時間的重度抑鬱
no period of deep depression
沒有家庭成員突然離異
no withdrawal from family members
沒有心血來潮的愛的表示
No spontaneous proclamations of love.
心血來潮的愛的表示
Spontaneous proclamations of love?
有時候  一個要自殺的人
Sometimes a suicidal person
在決定自殺的前幾天
in the days leading up to the act
會動不動對家人表示"我愛你"
will just blurt out "I love you" to family
這算是一種告別
sort of like a goodbye.
我們先調查最近的兩位受害人
We'll start with the latest two victims.
如果他們是自殺的  那我們得查出誘因
If they were suicides   let's find out what drove them to it.
懷俄明州  尤因塔縣  治安官辦公室
你們好  我是Rhonda Samuel
Hello. Rhonda Samuel.
你好  我是Jareau探員  我們通過電話
Hi. Agent Jareau. We spoke on the phone.
感謝你們特意趕來
Thanks for coming out.
大家聽說你們要來  都為之一振
My county's getting pretty shook up.
有個記者一直不斷來電話
I got this reporter won't stop calling.
我拖著他沒理
I'm holding him off   but he's connecting the dots
但他從案子的數量上推測出其中的關聯
on the number of suicides.
我該回復他嗎
Should I call him back?
不  目前不要
No   not just yet.
對於何時向公眾公佈信息
We need to be very careful
我們得倍加小心
about when we release this information.
對這些死亡事件進行媒體渲染
Sensationalizing these deaths
可能會對其他孩子造成連鎖效應
may cause a domino effect with other kids.
專業術語叫做自殺傳染
The term is suicide contagion.
在一個群體中
The spread of suicidal thoughts
傳播自殺思想
among a group of people
有時會導致出現模仿行為
that sometimes results in copycat acts.
這種現象在青少年案件中尤為普遍
It's especially prevalent in teen cases
還有研究表明  一旦出現媒體報道
and studies suggest that media coverage
通常會提高死亡率
is sometimes associated with more deaths.
有沒有適合讓我們工作的地方
Is there a good place for me to set up?
我們沒有很正規的指揮中心
Don't have much of a command center.
沒事  設備我都帶來了
Oh   fret not. I got my own command center.
我只需要電源
I just need your juice.
沒問題
You got it.
你好  先生
Hello   sir.
我們是聯邦調查局行為分析科的探員
We're with the FBI Behavioral Analysis Unit.
她明年高中畢業  她一直很興奮
She was so excited about graduating high school
她等不及要考大學了
She couldn't wait for her sats.
Trish有和誰在交往嗎
Was Trish dating anybody?
沒有
No.
Billy Sullivan
Billy Sullivan.
-難道就是那個  -沒錯
- It that who she's-  - Yes.
怎麼回事  Leake先生
What is it   Mr. Leake?
她上個月短信費超了100美元
She ran up over $100 texting last month.
我們沒收了她的手機  還禁了她的足
And   we   um   we grounded her and we took away her cell.
不是我們  是我
Not we. Me.
是我的主意
I did that.
你怎麼不告訴我她有個男友
Why didn't you tell me she had a boyfriend?
因為你會抓狂
Because you would have freaked out.
我不會
No   I wouldn't.
你現在就抓狂了
You are right now.
不是因為得知她有個男友
Not because she had a boyfriend
而是她的死很可能是我
because I may have caused--
Leake先生  如果你女兒的確是自殺
Mr. Leake   if your daughter committed suicide
那並不僅是因為某些家庭懲罰
it wouldn't have been because of some punishment.
這其中有更複雜的原因
It's so much more complicated than that.
如果
If?
您說什麼
Excuse me?
你剛才說如果她的確是自殺
You said "If" She committed suicide.
能帶我們去看看Trish的房間嗎
Would you mind showing us Trish's room?
好
Yeah.
當然  這邊走
Sure. It's this way.
我就知道他不是自殺
I knew he didn't kill himself.
他不會讓我們承受這種悲傷
He wouldn't do that to us.
不好意思
I'm sorry?
你們來這兒的原因就是如此
Uh   that's   uh   that's why you're here.
聯邦調查局不會調查
The FBI wouldn't be investigating
一起自殺案件的吧
a suicide   right?
其實則不然
That's not exactly true.
有些時候  我們的確會進行一些
Uh   sometimes we do what's called
可疑死亡案件調查
an equivocal death investigation
試圖查清死亡原因
to try to figure out the manner of death.
結果可能
It may turn out that--
我們會盡量幫你們查清
Our investigation will try and sort it all out for you.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
她很多才多藝
She certainly was accomplished.
她的日記沒有反常之處
There's nothing unusual in her diary--
沒有憤怒  焦慮
No fury   no angst.
你們一定要查遍她的私人物品嗎
Do you really have to go through all her personal stuff?
她很注重隱私
She was such a private girl.
很抱歉  我們必須這麼做
We are terribly sorry to have to do this.
我們也關心Trish
We care about Trish
我們想確保
And we want to make sure
這樣的夢魘不會降落到別人的身上
this doesn't happen to anybody else's daughter.
Leake先生和Leake夫人
Mr. And mrs. Leake
有張表需要兩位填寫
There's a form I need you both to fill out.
能跟我來嗎
Can you come with me?
如果有任何需要
If you need anything...
謝謝
Thank you.
他們真可憐
Those poor people.
希望我們沒有給他們帶來更大傷害
I just hope we haven't made it worse for them.
可能嗎
Could we?
真的不用給各位拿點喝的嗎
Are you sure I can't get anyone something to drink?
不用了  謝謝
Yes   ma'am   thank you.
如果你改變主意
Well   if you change your mind...
你覺得她是被謀殺的嗎
Do you think someone killed her?
夫人
Ma'am...
Sharon
Sharon...
你為什麼說 "如果"她是自殺的
Why would you say "If" She committed suicide?
夫人  我
Ma'am   I--
為什麼她會這麼說
I mean   why would she say that
如果她不認為  如果她覺得
If she didn't think-- if she thought--
你為什麼這麼說
Why would you say that?
個人物品顯示她當時很自如
Well   personal touches show she was comfortable here.
入學備考書籍  大學名冊
SAT prep books   college brochures.
她不像個有高自殺傾向的人
She's a low suicide risk if I ever saw one.
確實  很明顯
Yeah   I think it's pretty obvious
Trish的生活很充實
Trish had everything to live for.
或許Garcia能從筆記本塈銗X
Maybe garcia will find something on the laptop
我們沒發現的東西
That we're not seeing here.
好的
Ok.
沒有隱匿之處
There's no secret hiding places.
也沒有毒品用具
Or drug paraphernalia.
這是Ryan的女友嗎
Is this ryan's girlfriend?
她叫Shaunna
Uh   Shaunna.
他們感情很好
They seemed really good together.
他和Trish Leake交往過嗎
Did he ever date trish leake?
之前沒聽說過這個名字
I never heard of trish leake
直到週五在醫院見到她的父母
Until...When we met her parents at the hospital   uh   Friday.
看來他成績很好
Seems like he got pretty good grades.
還有封球隊教練寫的信
And this letter from the football coach?
Barswell教練要他明年加入校橄欖球隊
Uh   coach barswell wanted him to... be in varsity next year.
四分衛
Quarterback.
Ryan的電腦呢
Uh   where is ryan's computer?
家庭娛樂室埵酗@部
Um   we have--we have one in the family room.
他沒有個人電腦嗎
He didn't have his own?
我們擔心他上網時沒人看著
We were worried about   uh   unsupervised online time
所以要他在家人面前上網
So we wanted him in the middle of everyone.
我能帶你們去看看
I can--I can go show you.
如果告訴我們IP地址
Actually   if you just get us the   uh
我們的技術員可以
Network ip address   I believe our technical analyst
遠程控制檢查電腦
Can go over it off site.
如果能證明Ryan不是自殺
If it helps prove that ryan didn't kill himself
要什麼都可以
You can have anything you need.
準備好探究Trish的網上世界了嗎
Hey   you ready to delve into trish leake's online world?
你指的是極有能力
If by ready you mean extremely capable
但又不太情願吧
and even more reluctant.
差不多
Yeah   something like that.
Leakes一家怎麼樣了
How are the leakes holding out?
恢復得還好
Oh   probably as well as can be expected.
他們很堅強
Yeah. They're strong people.
那就好
Good.
真奇怪
Well   that's weird.
-什麼也沒有  -什麼
- There's nothing here. - What?
沒什麼可用的
Nothing useful?
什麼也沒有
Nothing at all.
連根目錄都沒有
Look   there's no root directory
也沒有操作系統
There's no operating system.
註冊表貌似空無一物
The registry appears to be blank.
可她幹嘛要裝一部裸機
But why would she have an empty computer set up?
我沒說是裸機  只說貌似空無一物
I did not say empty   I said appears to be blank.
什麼意思
Meaning?
意思是我要花點時間
I'm gonna need a little while.
JJ
Jj.
我知道  我不該說"如果"
I know. I know. I never should have said "If."
相信我  我絕不想
Believe me   the last thing I want
給這些家人雪上加霜
Is to make things worse for these families.
我沒有暗示這不是自殺
Look   I'm not invested in these not being suicides.
我只是想盡量
I just...want to try and
讓這週五不會跟上週五一樣
keep this Friday from being like the last two.
搞定了
I got it!
是個簡單木馬病毒作怪
It was--it was just a basic trojan horse.
只隱藏了磁盤目錄並沒有刪除
It just hid the directories   didn't erase them.
天啊
Oh   god.
怎麼了
What is it?
她死當晚上過窒息遊戲網
She was on a choking game site the night she died.
什麼東西
A what?
是個小孩玩的遊戲
Uh   it's a game kids play where
讓自己窒息以求亢奮
they choke themselves to get a buzz   to get high.
他們稱之為"好娃娃亢奮"
They call it the good kids' high.
即使沒有吸毒
You get lightheaded and a sense of euphoria even though
也能產生興奮感
no actual drugs are involved.
很多高中生會玩
It's something kids in high school play.
Ryan有電腦嗎
Did ryan have a computer?
他房堥S有
Not in his room.
-有遊戲機嗎  -有
- What about a gaming system? - Yeah   he did.
青少年會想方設法上網
Teenagers will find a way to get online.
我有IP地址
I have the   uh   ip address.
這個有用
Oh. That will help.
猜中  Ryan當晚也上了同一網站
Bingo. Ryan was on the same site on the same night.
這不是自殺
It wasn't suicide.
稍等  上面有語音
Hang on   this is a text to voice icon.
聽聽怎麼回事
Let's see what happens.
快試試
Come on   try it.
我們都試了  你敢嗎
We all do it. I dare you.
你敢嗎
I dare you?
有人精心策劃
Someone was orchestrating this
故意讓小孩扼死自己
Purposely getting the kids to choke themselves.
一定要關門
Make sure you close the door.
明天是重要一晚
Tomorrow's the big night.
我們都會玩這個遊戲
We're all gonna play the game.
這個遊戲有個小群體
There's a whole subculture around this game.
有各種名字  經常在派對玩
They make up names for it   they do it at parties.
有人教唆這堛漱p孩
But someone is daring these kids in this area
玩這種遊戲
To play the game.
這是個競賽
It's a contest.
還有規則
And there are rules.
加油  Evans高中  接受挑戰
Come on   evans high   this is the big one.
Garfield高中上周擊敗Casper高中
Garfield edged out casper high last week.
你會讓他們踩扁我們嗎
You gonna let them diss us?
踩扁  真像小孩的口氣
Diss--sounds like a kid.
還有誰會讓學校間互相較量
Who else would pit schools against each other?
魯莽少年比賽
Reckless teenage competition.
本週五取得最長亢奮時間的學校勝出
The school that logs the most high time this Friday wins.
週五  明天
Friday   tomorrow.
快叫朋友來參加
Get your friends on board.
練習越多  亢奮越久
Practice makes the high last longer.
務必獨自嘗試  用網絡攝影機拍下過程
Gotta do it alone and video it with your webcam
上傳至本網站  以便記錄
And upload it to the site for it to count.
獨自嘗試需要繩子
Doing it alone requires ligatures.
他基本上是慫恿小孩
He's basically encouraging
用最致命的方式玩
them to play the deadliest form of the game
且沒人能救醒他們
With no one there to revive them.
Garcia  關掉這個網站
Garcia   shut the site down.
長官  我完全能做到
Sir   I can totally do that
但我覺得不能這麼做
But I don't think you want me to.
為什麼
Why?
網站是目前唯一追查嫌犯的線索
Right now this site is our only way to track the unsub
如果我介入  他肯定會察覺
And if I cut into it   he will certainly know
我們在關注他
We're watching him
這樣一來  他會關掉網站
In which case he'll shut it down bring it back up
簡單改寫代碼
And he'll write a simple change in code
以更隱蔽方式重操舊業
In a more covert fashion.
而且不清楚有多少服務器
Plus there's no telling how many servers it's replicated on   anyway.
你說得對
You're right.
我們可以做側寫了
We're ready to give the profile.
這幾起謀殺案的不明嫌犯可能是一名少年
We believe the unsub responsible for these deaths may be a teenager.
他為人孤僻  不參與團體運動或活動
He's a loner. He doesn't participate in team sports
性格內向  自尊心很弱
Or group activities. He's withdrawn   very low self-esteem.
唯一與人互動的方式是上網
His only form of pure interaction is online.
從事能讓別人注意他的活動
He engages in activity that draws attention to himself
但又與同齡人有隔閡
Yet isolates him from his peers.
父母及老師應注意
Parents and teachers should watch out
以下可疑跡象
for the warning signs--
眼睛佈滿血絲  頸部有傷痕
Kids with bloodshot eyes   marks on their necks
或是有劇烈頭痛  眼神迷茫的孩子
severe headaches   disorientation.
他在現實生活中把自己歸為失敗者
In real life   he considers himself a loser.
在網絡  他用繩索讓自己變得強大
In cyberspace   he can pull strings   make himself powerful.
這孩子知道有別的孩子因他喪生嗎
Does this kid know that other kids are dying because of him?
他讓自己窒息並鼓勵其他人也這麼做
He's choking himself and daring others to do it
所以這極有可能是過失殺人案
So we're most likely looking at reckless homicides here.
如果各位發現任何異常或可疑之處
It you see anything that's unusual or suspicious
請致電治安官辦公室
Just call the Sheriff's department
我們會盡全力給予幫助
And we will try to direct you as best we can.
謝謝大家
Thank you.
我們已經盡可能告知了更多家長
Well   we've told as many parents as we could.
你覺得有用嗎
Do you think it helped?
不如讓孩子們明白這些更有效
Not as much as getting through to the kids will.
窒息與過度換氣  這兩者
Two different mechanisms   strangulation and hyperventilation
都會造成腦部缺氧
Create the same effect- oxygen deprivation in the brain.
喂  小朋友
Hey   kid.
這可不好
Not a good idea.
讓我看下
Let me see it.
這哥們是從哪顆星球冒出來的
"What planet is this dude from?"
他不想讓咱們贏那個比賽
"He doesn't want us to win the contest."
我
Um...I--uh--uh--
我覺得更準確的表達應該是
I think the more accurate statement would be
他不想讓我們參加那個比賽
"He doesn't want us to participate in the contest at all."
這是Ryan的桌子  對吧
This was Ryan's desk   right?
他以前坐在這兒吧
This is where Ryan sat?
你們記得Ryan吧
You guys remember Ryan.
他踢足球  帶Shaunna去舞會
He   uh   played football. Took--took Shaunna to prom.
我猜你們中有些還跟他是朋友
I'm assuming that some of you were probably even friends with Ryan.
Ryan也曾想贏這比賽
Ryan wanted to win the contest   too
但是當他自縊時
But the way Ryan choked himself
腦部的供氧被切斷
He cut off all the oxygen to his brain
這向心臟傳輸了求救信號
which sent a distress signal to his heart
使得心臟跳動遲緩
Slowing it down.
接著  大腦為自我保護
Then his brain   in an effort to preserve itself
停止了所有非必要的身體功能
shut off all no n-essential bodily functions.
手臂  雙腿無法動彈
His arms gave out   his legs gave out
也就是說  他沒法解開脖子上的繩結
which means he couldn't loosen the tie around his neck
而此時  恐慌襲來
At which point panic set in.
Ryan最終心搏停止
And in Ryan's case   it escalated to cardiac arrest.
也就是說他的心臟停跳
Which means that his heart stopped.
繼而發生腦損傷
Brain damage began
在四分鐘內
And within 4 minutes
他就已經完全腦死亡了
He is completely and totally brain dead.
他在恐懼和巨大的痛苦中死去
He died scared and probably in a lot of pain
原以為一切盡在掌控卻無法終止
And unable to stop what he thought he completely control of
而所有這些都是因為他要參加那個
All because he wanted to participate
我覺得爛到透頂的遊戲
In what I consider to be a pretty- -pretty lame game.
所以  你的短信還真說對了
So   I mean   your text is actually completely accurate.
我不想你們贏下那個比賽
I don't want you to win the contest
因為我壓根不希望你們參加
Because I don't want you to play the game.
你們還真信這廢話
You all believe this crap?
你不信嗎
You don't?
怎麼不跟大家說說你是怎麼認為的
Why don't you come up here and tell us what you think.
好啊
Whatever.
站住
Hey! Hey   come here!
Come here!
小子  停下
Kid   stop!
沒事吧
You all right?
-放開我  -放鬆點
- Let me go! - Just relax.
-放開我  -別動
- Let me go! Then stop fighting.
別動
Stop fighting. Stop it.
放開我
Let me go.
沒事的
It's all right.
還好吧
You ok?
是的  沒事
Yeah. I'm fine.
你跑什麼
Why'd you run?
Morgan  看看他的脖子
Morgan   look at his neck.
讓我看看你的脖子
Let me look at your neck.
別碰它
Don't touch that!
我剛怎麼說的
Hey   what'd I say?
放鬆
Relax.
顏色不同表明正處於不同的恢復階段
Different colors mean different stages of healing.
你這麼做很長時間了  對嗎
You've been doing this to yourself for long time   havn't you?
大腦一定已經飽受折磨了
There's no telling how much his brain has suffered.
Reid博士
Dr. Reid.
你覺得就是他嗎
You think it's him?
很可能
He's a pretty likely candidate.
我是Wilson Summers
I'm Wilson Summers.
學校打電話給我說我兒子受了傷
The school called and said my son was injured.
Will
Will.
-你認識他  -工作上認識的
- You know him? - Professionally.
他在消防局工作
He works for the Fire Department.
治安官
Sheriff.
這是Reid博士
This is Dr. Reid.
我兒子還好吧  醫生
Ahh. Is my son all right   doctor?
事實上  我不是醫生
Actually   um   I'm not that type of doctor.
我為FBI工作
I'm with the FBI.
FBI嗎
FBI?
你兒子一直在自扼頸部
Your son Christopher has been choking himself.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你知道最近有孩子死去的事情吧
You know the kids that have died recently?
那些自殺
The suicides.
他們可能不是自殺
They may not be suicides.
一個他這年紀孩子在玩的遊戲
It's a game that kids his age tend to play
他們使自己昏迷
Where they force themselves to pass out
為了達到興奮刺激的感覺
For the   uh   the buzz that it gives them.
Christopher穿哥特裝多久了
How long has Christopher been dressed in Gothic fashion
塗黑指甲  畫黑眼圈
The black nails and the eyes and...
有一陣了
A while.
他過得很不容易
He's been having a rough time.
怎麼了
Why's that?
幾年前 他的母親去世了
His mother died a few years ago
之後他就一直穿黑衣服
And he's been wearing black ever since.
他常耗在電腦上嗎
Does Christopher spend a lot of time on the computer?
只要一醒來
Just every waking...
為什麼這麼問
Why?
我們認為你的兒子可能建立了一個網站
We think your son may have created a website
鼓勵孩子們在這個窒息比賽媊v爭
Encouraging kids to compete in this choking contest.
你說什麼
What are you saying?
爸爸
Dad.
夥計
Hey   buddy.
帶他進去
Take him inside.
你的兒子要做些檢查
Your son needs to go in for some tests.
Will
Will.
等他檢查完
When he's done
我們要讓他來我辦公室談談
We're gonna need to talk to him down in my office.
一整晚都沒有動靜
There hasn't been any activity all night.
還沒到週五
It's not Friday yet.
很感謝你讓我們查他的電腦
I appreciate you letting us take a look at his computer.
Rhonda  你們錯了
You're making a mistake   Rhonda.
Chris是個好孩子
Chris is a good kid.
我真心希望你是對的
I really hope that's true.
給你
Here it is.
一旦真相大白
Well   if this all works out
我保證馬上還給他
I promise I'll give it back to him as soon as possible.
Christopher  我們知道
Christopher   we know you've been
你母親去世後你過得很艱難
Going through a lot since your mother died.
孩子 當發生不幸 我們會沮喪
When bad things happen to us   we get frustrated   kid.
而有時候我們會宣洩出來  做些不好的事
Sometimes we act out and we do things we're not proud of.
他心不在焉
He's not very engaged.
給他些時間
Give them some time.
快要週五了
Well   it's almost Friday.
沒剩多少時間
We don't have any time.
只要他呆在這  就沒法在網站上行動
Well   as long as he's here   he can't post Anything new to his website.
沒錯  但其他孩子還是會玩那遊戲
True   but the kids are still gonna play the game.
你們要的全部背景資料
Here's the full background you wanted.
多謝
Thank you.
難怪他這麼孤獨
No wonder he's a loner.
他母親去世後  他們搬了三次家
They've moved 3 times since his mother died.
失去了同齡人的幫助支持
Cut off his peer support.
兩年換了三所學校
3 new schools in 2 years.
對一個孩子來說要適應太不容易了
That is a lot of adjustment for a kid to have to make.
我想讓你知道我們會沒收你的電腦
I want you to know that we're going to be confiscating your computer.
我們的分析人員會做全面調查
Our analyst is going through all of it.
來揭開真相
So that we can uncover the truth.
當然
Sure you will.
真相麼
Truth.
看起來他對我們會發現什麼並不擔心
He doesn't seem worried about us finding anything.
他們溝通得不是很順暢
They aren't building any rapport.
他們回來了
They're back.
天吶  christopher這孩子真古怪
Mary   this christopher kid is fantastical.
他有一個分區硬盤
He's got a segmented hard drive
強大的防火牆  超長的密碼
Serious firewalls   major league encryption.
沒有必要這樣
No reason for all that unless
除非他隱藏了些重要的東西
he's hiding something serious
那麼  這就是他不著急的原因
Ok   so that's why he isn't worried.
這個是  不正常的
This is--uhh! Unusual.
我發動的每一次攻擊都馬上被擊破
Every attack I launch is shot down immediately.
那是什麼
What's that?
有人剛剛上傳了一段新的視頻到這個遊戲網站上
Somebody just uploaded a new video to the game site.
12點01分
it's 12:01.
--現在星期五  --他們在玩
It's Friday. They're playing.
他們中遲早有人會出事的
It's only a matter of time before some of them go wrong.
夥計們  我現在沒有任何辦法了
Guys   I'm gonna keep dead-ending on this
我得弄清楚他的安全系統是如何設置的
Until I get a beat on how he set up his security system.
希望你有B計劃
Hope you got a plan "B."
Garcia  我覺得你跟其他人比
Garcia   I think that this kid
和這個孩子會有更多的共同語言
will relate to you better than anybody else.
我想讓你跟他談談  看看你能不能讓他開口
I want you to talk to him   see if you can get him to open up.
呃...
Um.
長官  我以前沒幹過這個
Sir   I have never done that before.
我搞砸了怎麼辦
What if I mess up?
你沒問題的
You'll be fine.
老弟  我叫 Penelope
Hi there. I'm Penelope.
名字不錯
Good for you.
介意我坐這兒嗎
Can I sit down?
你是個警察
You're the cop.
你看我像警察嗎
Um   I look like a cop to you?
是啊  你不是嗎
Yeah. What   you aren't?
不是
No.
聯邦調查局的技術員
FBI tech analyst.
我只是可以享用官方網絡數據庫
I just have some administrative cyber crud
來調查你
To go over with you.
一個怪胎女孩
Just a geekette.
挺酷的
Cool.
你悶悶不樂
You are glum.
時間可以撫平一切
Time is a great healer.
你不瞭解我的感受
You have no idea how I feel.
我在像你這麼大的時候
I lost my mom and my dad
失去了我的父母
when I was like you age though
我也不知道  我想我很瞭解你的感受
I don't know. I think I have a pretty good idea.
我感覺非常孤獨
And I felt totally alone.
直到我在網上安家
Till I found netizens.
一直都這樣
Btdt.(Been There Done That)
喂  我  我沒騙你
Hey   I'm... I'm not lying.
一切都會好起來的
It'll totally get better.
順便說下  我喜歡你的穿孔
Btw   I like your nails.
謝了
Thanks.
你是哥特迷嗎
You into goth?
我現在不應該迷這個
You know   I don't think I'm supposed to be anymore
但是我還是很喜歡
But the love is still there.
那你是聯邦探員嗎
So you're FBI?
我知道這很不正常  可我就是喜歡
Yeah   I know. It's crazy   but I love it.
我也很喜歡你的耳環
I enjoy your earring   too.
從哪堬^來的
Where did you score that?
易趣上
Ebay.
應該是加勒比海盜
It's supposed to be johnny d.'s
強尼德普戴的那個
From that pirate movie.
太厲害了
Most awesome.
她做得不錯
She's good.
她建立的溝通是Morgan和Reid所不能得
Established rapport when  and reid couldn't.
我們應該每次都帶著她
We should bring her out all the time.
那麼  你的全方位數據保護加密系統
Ok   your whole pgp disc encryption system
簡直酷斃了
Is like crazy impressive.
是啊  我對那東西很著迷
Yeah   I'm into that kind of stuff.
東西  老弟  你沒明白我有多麼嫉妒
Stuff? Dude   you do not understand. I am jealous.
那可是最時髦的技術
That is state-of-the-art technology
一般人可玩不轉
The feeb does not have.
隨便吧
Whatever.
那麼  你是怎麼得到你的代理服務器的呢
Ok. How did you get your anonymizing service?
從一個網友的一個鏈接
I got it from some link from some dude online.
問這個幹什麼啊
What do you care?
我只是覺得你設置整個系統的過程太酷了
I just think it's uber cool how you set your whole system up.
就像個碎紙機一樣
Like how you use an e-shredder
根本查不出你在網上的活動
To obliterate your net activity
並且有個雨刮器如同一個輔助垃圾處理器
And a window wiper as your secondary trash eraser.
-誰做的  -所有人都這麼做
- Who does that?   - Everybody does that.
審問結束了
The interview's over.
審問?
Interview?
-我剛想  -他父親求援了
- I was just--   - His father invoked.
老爸
Dad.
我要給你找個律師
I'm getting you a lawyer.
你母親去世後我把事情搞的很糟  讓你失望了
I screwed up and failed you when your mother died.
這次不會的
Not this time.
如果你們對他沒有任何指控的話
Unless you people have something to charge him with.
我們要走了
We're leaving.
回頭見  P姐姐
Syl   miss p.
順便說一下
By the way
我確實懷念我媽媽
I do miss my mom.
她不是你的朋友
She's not your friend.
你是來套你話的
She was trying to trick you.
抱歉  長官  我盡力了
Sir   I'm sorry   I tried.
他願意求援就求援吧
If he invokes   he invokes.
你集中精力破解密碼吧
Concentrate on cracking the encryption.
好的
Yeah.
從頻繁程度上來看
Judging by sheer volume
Christophe的母親病情很嚴重
Christopher's mother was sick quite a bit.
他父親多次送她去急診室
His father brought her into the er repeatedly.
她每次的情況都非常糟糕
She's described as being violently ill each time.
在重癥監護室幾天後就奇跡般的康復了
A couple of days in the icu   miraculous recovery
就是不停的反覆發生
Only to be repeated time and again.
沒有診斷意見  沒有確切的誘因
No diagnosis   no discernable cause.
有一個視頻正在上傳
There's another video going up.
這是半小時內的第四個孩子
That's 4 kids playing in half an hour.
有幾個孩子在那所學校上學
How many kids go to this school?
整個縣都是它的學區 近2000人
Its catchment is the whole county. It's almost 2  000.
Garcia  我們急需
Garcia   we really need to
得到這個網站的管理權限
gain administrative access to the website.
我會寫下一些Christopher
I've written down a number of things
可能作為密碼的東西
Christopher may have used as the password.
我已經排除了生日和節日
I've already eliminated birthdays   holidays
寵物名  和流行文化名城
Pet names   and pop culture icons.
不  一些可憐的事情發生在他身上
No   there was something pathetic about him
而非犯罪
Not criminal.
當他離開的時候  他說他懷念他的母親
When he was leaving   he said he misses his mom.
他母親叫什麼名字
What's his mother's name?
Cynthia Summers
Cynthia Summers.
就是它
That's it.
好的  用管理員權限登錄
All right   log in as administrator
切斷主要資源
and shut down the main resource
在做了
Already on it   my friend.
孩子們還在通過獨立的服務器上傳
Kids are still posting videos through independent servers.
把網站歷史記錄調出來
Pull up the website history.
看看能不能獲得些以往內容發佈的記錄
See if you can learn anything from historical posts.
Christopher的急診病志顯示
Christopher's er eval shows his bruises
他的瘀傷來自於長期的手掐和捆綁
Were caused by manual and ligature strangulation over time.
看這個  他還有
Take a look at this. He's also shown
胸部的陳舊性瘀傷
To have layered bruising on his sternum.
看起來像個急救心臟起搏器
It looks like a cpr artifact.
但是這堥S有急救記錄
But there's no record of resuscitations.
等等  所有這些信息傳輸
Wait   all these transmissions
都源於同一個管理員嗎
Are transcripts of the same administrator?
是的  這堨u有一個源頭
Yeah   there's only one handle.
那就怪了  他的語氣在文章埵傅雂
This is weird. In the posts his voice changes.
他每次都引用更多的文章  更加滴水不漏
At times he's using more articles   more precise verbiage
就像一直防備著我們
Like he's trying to throw us off.
對於一個孩子來說這太狡猾了
That's pretty sophisticated behavior for a kid.
一個作者可以偽裝他的寫作風格
A writer can disguise his own writing style
讓人感覺他更年輕或者教育程度更低
To make himself appear younger or less educated.
是啊  但是反過來
Yeah   but it's virtually impossible
想讓你的風格變得更成熟或者
To pull off making yourself appear older
受教育程度更高就不太可能了
And more educated than you actually are.
事實上這埵釣潃茪ㄕP的寫作風格
There are actually 2 distinct writing style.
兩個作者用同一個網名
2 writers using the same screen name--
一個少年和一個成人
One teen and one adult.
Christopher被一個成年人操控著
Christopher was being manipulated by an adult.
她母親的死是一個典型的
The mother's death is a textbook case
孟喬森代理綜合癥  被毒死的
Of munchausen by proxy. Surreptitious poisoning.
這個孩子被窒息然後搶救回來很多次
The kid has been choked and revived on multiple occasions.
你說過他父親在消防隊工作  對吧
You said the father worked for the fire department   right?
是的  有幾個月的時間了
Yeah   for a couple of months now.
--哪個部門  --急救組
In what capacity? As an EMT.
急救組  他就是我們的嫌犯
EMT. That's our unsub.
Christopher不清楚
Christopher didn't even understand
他電腦堛熔M除系統
The wiping systems on his computer.
是他父親假裝成同學在網上發帖
So the father poses as a classmate
邀請這些當地的孩子參加遊戲
And invites local kids to join the game.
增加賭注並且鼓勵他們
Bumps up the stakes and encourages them
使用最危險的方式
To use their riskiest methods.
他在週五執勤
He works on Friday nights.
也就是說他能接到這些孩子的急救任務
Which means he gets called out to do the rescues.
他不僅僅是收集視頻
He's not just collecting video tapes.
他的孟喬森綜合癥在升級
His munchausen has evolved.
我去給他的車發個通緝令
I'll put out an apb for his truck.
他會找一個地方來下載這些視頻
He'll find a place to download the video tapes.
那相當於他的戰利品
They're his trophies.
之後  他會清理掉所有人證物證
After that   he'll clean up his mess.
Christopher是唯一對他有威脅的目擊證人
Christopher's the only witness against him.
安全
Clear.
Clear!
過來看看
You need to see this.
這有很多光盤
There's dozens of discs here.
當時我就在這房間
I was right here.
可我甚至都沒有看看周圍
I never even looked around.
我們只得到搜查手提電腦的許可
Well   we only had consent for the laptop
而且他知道電腦加密過了
and he knew it was encrypted.
我們當時沒有合法原因來申請搜查許可
We didn't have probable cause for a warrant.
Summers先生沒有機會回來拿他的這些戰利品
Mr. Summers didn't have a chance to come back and get his trophies.
今晚他絕對會從網上下載那些視頻
He'll definitely try to download the videos tonight.
那個孩子用盡手段  就為了能夠活下去
This kid was doing everything he could just to survive.
過度的虐待導致他條件反射地包庇他父親
The extreme abuse conditioned him to shield his father.
當他爸爸走進來的時候
When his father came in the room
他看上去徹底放鬆了
he seemed genuinely relieved.
他卸下了負擔
His burden had been lifted.
他爸爸救他的時候他簡直興高采烈
He was elated when his father rescued him.
我們要重新思考每個細節了
We need to rethink everything.
我們要去哪
Where are we going?
去見你媽媽
To see your mom.
把注意力集中到他的態度舉止上
Now   let's focus on the behavior.
他屬於什麼行為模式
What's the pattern?
事情發展到一觸即發  父親就會離開
Things boil over   the father moves on.
新的城鎮  新的虐待方式
New town   new sadistic M.O.
Christopher知道他爸爸的行為模式
Christopher knows his father's pattern.
這樣我們才能找出真相
So that we can uncover the truth.
當然了
Sure you will.
真相
Truth.
在他看來  這件事將永無止境
In his mind   it will never end.
除非Christopher已經決定親手結束一切
Unless Christopher's decided to end it.
-Garcia  -是的  長官
- Garcia? - Yes   sir?
你和Christopher談話的時候
When you were talking to Christopher
他有沒有說過一些話  暗示他要放棄了
Did he say anything to you to suggest that he was giving up?
放棄
Giving up?
他有沒有試著道別
Was he trying to say good-bye?
我不懂
I don't understand.
他給你什麼東西了嗎
Did he give you anything?
是啊  你怎麼知道的
Yeah. How did you know that?
他給你什麼了
What did he give you?
我們說話的時候
When--when we were talking
他給了我這個海盜耳環
he gave me this pirate's earring.
他已經打定主意了  自殺
He's made up his mind. Suicide--
是戰勝他虐待狂父親的唯一方法
the only victory over his sadistic father.
他也許還把自殺當作是和他母親的重逢
He may also see it as reuniting with his mother.
父親會從網上下載
The father's going to want to download
那些視頻  Garcia
those videos from somewhere   Garcia
我們要阻止他
And we got to stop that process.
我已經在處理了
I'm already on that.
我把那個網址替換成了釣魚網站[仿冒網]
I replaced the website with a phishing site
我正在給那個服務器加載釣魚網
I'm downloading it to the servers now.
等他在網站登陸的時候
When he logs onto that website
他會轉而進入到我們的服務器
He's going to be rerouted to our server
我們就可以追蹤到他的信息
and we can capture his information.
密切注意那個網站  Garcia
Stay on that site   Garcia.
好
Yeah.
我們走  來吧
Let's go. Come on.
這可以為我們爭取一些時間
It will buy us some time.
他們的目的地是哪
等等  那個母親呢
Where are they headed?
Wait. What about the mother?
一切都是因她而起
It's all about the mother.
Garcia  Cynthia Summers埋在哪堣F
Garcia   where is Cynthia Summers buried?
等等
Give me a second.
對於Christopher
You know   for Christopher
墓地是慰藉之地
a cemetery would be a place of refuge
可對於他爸爸來說
But for the father...
他再次回到了屍體處理地點
he's revisiting a body disposal site.
Oaklawn墓地  位於這堜MGlenrock之間
Oaklawn cemetery   halfway between here and Glenrock.
好  他一定很願意和他爸爸去那
Ok. He would willingly go there with his father.
不過他爸爸還是需要下載視頻
Well   the father still needs to download the videos.
而他需要電源
And he might need a power source.
有一個小教堂  為葬禮準備的
There's a chapel. They use it for burials.
出發  Garcia  我們會在車媮p繫你
Let's go. Garcia   we'll call you from the car.
你知道程序的  不會很久
You know the drill. This won't take long.
那是他的越野車
That's his suv.
說吧  Garcia
yeah   Garcia?
長官  Summers先生剛剛登陸了
Sir   Mr. Summers just logged on.
他被釣魚網站追蹤到了
He's caught in the phishing site.
他是不是在下載視頻
Is he downloading the videos?
是的  不過他只能看到雪花而已
He's trying to   but all he's going to get is snow.
拜託
Oh   come on.
我不想死
I don't want to die.
你的死期由我決定
I decide when you die.
聯邦探員
FBI!
你們沒事吧
You guys good?
非常感謝
Well   I can't tell you
你們來幫忙
how much I appreciate y'all coming out here.
我只是慶幸結局不是太壞
I'm just glad it ended up ok.
拜託
Oh   come on.
小小城鎮堛漯v安官向聯邦探員求助
Small-time county sheriff calls the FBI
還是關於潛在性自殺案
about potential suicides
而你們卻放下手邊的工作
and you drop what you're doing
過來這
and you come here?
我們會對任何級別的執法部門提供幫助
We're an asset for all levels of law enforcement.
這是我們的職責所在
It's what we do.
讓人欽佩
Well   it's incredible.
謝謝
Thank you.
你想和我們一起來嗎
Would you like to come with us?
我們要去通知家屬事情的真相
We're going to tell the parents what really happened.
不了  我們要啟程回去了
Uh   no. We need to be getting back.
你確定嗎
You sure?
我知道這無法挽回什麼
I mean   I know it won't bring them back
不過  我想讓他們知道這不是蓄意自殺
but I would think that knowing that it wasn't intentional
多少會帶來些安慰吧
might bring some level of comfort.
一定會的
It will   definitely.
你去吧  祝你好運  治安官
You go ahead. Good luck   sheriff.
謝謝
Well   thank you.
這是什麼
What is that?
這個叫星之謎
It's called a star puzzle.
這個基本上無解的
It's basically impossible to figure out.
你要把所有碎片拼到一起
You have to put all of the
組成一個完整的星形
pieces back together to form a perfect star.
不過這個遊戲的來源  是一個愛情傳說
But the origin of it is   um   kind of a romantic tale.
有一個年輕的王子
There was this young prince
他想捕獲王國堣@位
who wanted to win the heart
傾國傾城的少女的芳心
of the fairest maiden in the land
所以他爬上了王國中
So he climbed to the top of
最高的塔頂
the tallest tower in the kingdom
然後他為她抓到了一顆流星
and he caught a falling star for her.
不幸的是  他過於激動了  把流星掉到了地上
Unfortunately   he was so excited   he dropped it
於是那顆流星破碎成了這些碎片
and it smashed into all of these pieces
所以他發瘋般地把這些碎片又拼湊到一起
so he frantically put it back together again
來證明他對她不朽的愛意
to prove his undying love to her
而且他成功了
and he succeeded
最後他們幸福快樂地生活在了一起
and they lived happily ever after.
這一點都講不通啊
That doesn't make any sense.
什麼意思
What do you mean?
你不可能抓住流星的
You can't catch a falling star.
它在大氣層奡N燒成灰燼了
It would burn up in the atmosphere.
是  不過不是那個意思
Yeah   but it's not literal
Reid  那是個傳說
Reid. It's a fable.
可那並沒有什麼寓意啊
But there's no moral.
傳說都是有寓意的
Fables have morals.
好吧  這只是個小小的愛情故事
Ok. So it's just a romantic little story.
而且主旨在於  做到這件事幾乎不可能
And the point is   it's basically impossible to do
因為你需要把這些碎片收集起來
because you have to take all of those pieces
然後重新組合到一起  要準確
and put them together exactly...
你真是讓人恨得牙癢癢  Reid博士
There's a lot to hate about you   Dr. Reid.
試試跟他玩撲克牌
Play poker with him sometime.
試試跟他下國際象棋
Try playing chess with him.
或者圍棋[有"離開"之意]
Or go.
嘿
Hey.
嘿  喝咖啡嗎
Hey. Coffee?
多謝
Thanks.
我只是想謝謝你
I just wanted to say thank you.
要不是你要求進一步跟進的話
If you hadn't pushed it
我們不會來的
we would never have gone.
-Hotch  -JJ
- Hotch... - J.J.
你不用這樣的
You don't have to.
我11歲的時候
My sister gave this to me
我姐姐給了我這個
when I was 11.
有一天下午  她走進我的房間
She just came into my bedroom one afternoon
告訴我  不管發生什麼
and told me that no matter what happened
她是愛我的
She loved me.
這是她最心愛的項鏈
This was her favorite necklace
所以我告訴她我不能要
so I told her I couldn't take it
可她堅持給我
but she insisted.
當然了  我背地堥銋磭僆}心
I   of course   was secretly very happy
因為我一直想要一個和她一樣的項鏈
'cause I always wanted one just like hers.
那是最後一次  我再也沒有
That's the last time-- I never...
我很遺憾
I'm sorry.
我每天都會想她
I think about her every day.
會好起來的  Hotch
It does get better   Hotch.
失去自己心愛的人  真的很心痛
Losing someone is... never easy.
可總有一天
But one day
當你想起她的時候  心不會再那麼痛
you'll remember her   and it won't hurt.
總有一天你會釋然的
You'll be happy.
謝謝
Thank you.
謝謝你所做的一切
Thank you for everything.
"經歷是殘忍的老師  可你會從中有所收穫
"Experience is a brutal teacher   but you learn.
我的上帝  你有所獲悉嗎"  C.S. Lewis
my god   do you learn." C.S. 劉易斯.